proverbs31.org 2018-06-28

# Privacy Policy

#### **Information We Collect and Receive**

Proverbs 31 collects and retains information about you and your device when you visit or give us information through the Proverbs 31 website.

#### **Donor Privacy Policy**

Proverbs 31 Ministries uses your information to understand your needs and interests and provide you with better service.

We do not share or sell our donors' personal information. Any contribution information is kept in strict confidence and is not shared with anyone outside of Proverbs 31 Ministries.

This policy applies to all information received by Proverbs 31 Ministries, both online and offline. This privacy protection includes the Proverbs 31 Ministries' website, First 5 mobile application, as well as any electronic, written or oral communications.

Any online donation information received through a third party service provider will be used only for processing the donation.

#### **Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

When your computer or mobile device contacts our web servers, we collect usage information about how our visitors use and navigate the Proverbs 31 website. An anonymous profile is established based on your visit and information such as the frequency and length of your visit, browser type, referrer data identifying the web page visited prior or other method used to enter the site and subsequent to visiting our website and mobile applications.

  * **Location Information** We track location information based on IP address.

  * **Device Information** We record information about the device you use to access our services. Device information may include the type of device you use, the unique identifier of the device, or the network provider that you use.

#### **Personally Identifiable Information**

Personally identifiable information is data that can identify and individual, such as a name or an email address. It refers to information that can be used to distinguish or trace an individual's identity, either alone or when combined with other personal or identifying information that is linked or linkable to a specific individual. We collect this kind of information from you to facilitate transactions that require knowing who the individual is.

#### **Examples of times when we use personally identifiable information**

There are a few areas on our web sites that can require personally identifiable information. An email address is required to subscribe to our Encouraging for Today Devotions. Identifiable information like name and email are also required when joining an Online Bible Study, accessing files in our free resource library and giving to Proverbs 31 on any donation form. 

#### **Use of Cookies and Web Beacons**

Our Services use online technologies such as cookies and web beacons. These technologies are use in a variety of ways.

#### **Cookies**

Cookies are text files that are placed in your device's browser and are used to help recognize your browser across different web pages, websites, and browsing sessions. Cookies are stored on your device. We may use cookies together with other information to enhance and personalize your experience on our Services (or elsewhere online), including:

  * to authenticate your identity when you use our services

  * to remember your preferences and registration information

  * to measure and research the effectiveness of our services, advertisements, and communications

  * to customize the content and advertisements provided to you through our services.

#### **Web Beacons**

Web beacons are small pieces of code placed on web pages, videos, and in emails that can communicate information about your browser to our reporting tools. Beacons can be used, among other things, to count views of a web page or read an email.

#### **How We Use Your Information**

The information we collect is used to improve your Proverbs31.org experience. Visitors are provided products tailored especially for them, or to inform them about new features or services. 

While Proverbs 31 uses third party vendors to communicate with you or analytics reporting, your information, including your email address, will not be sold, shared or disclosed with any third party outside of the Proverbs 31 family unless otherwise noted in a specific consent or other entry, or as necessary to provide communications from Proverbs 31 through third party vendors. Proverbs 31 employs strict security measures to safeguard online transactions, and personal information is stored in a secured database and always sent via an encrypted channel.

#### **Advertising**

In some cases, Internet cookies and web beacons may be used to give you useful information through third party vendors and advertisements, including Google and Facebook. At times, you may see a Proverbs 31 ad on third party websites based on your web visit history to our website through these cookies.

#### **Preferences and Opting Out**

Users may opt-out of the use of their data for internet-based advertising.

You may opt out of a third party's vendor use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) page.

You may also opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting its [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads) page.

#### **Other Information You May Want**

_The Proverbs 31 Privacy Policy was updated effective 5/11/18._

#### **Contact us:**

If you have questions about our privacy policy, please contact us.

Proverbs 31 Ministries  
630 Team Rd., Suite 100  
Matthews, NC 28105  
Phone: 877-P31-HOME (877-731-4663)
